Summary: I am a data and analytics professional with more than 10 years of experience in data architecture and engineering, last 7 years working in banking and financial services industry.

I designed and delivered data solutions across major cloud data platforms, Azure, AWS, GCP, along with industry leading data governance, modeling, and business intelligence suites, such as Collibra, Erwin, PowerBi.

My managerial MBA skill set, complemented with TOGAF Enterprise Architecture acumen, allows me to create governance frameworks, secure senior management support and successfully deliver data transformation projects across large groups of stakeholders.

Leading people and efficiently delivering data initiatives, I excel at igniting cultural change and creating data driven organizations.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Enterprise Data Architect, Macquarie Group, banking and financial services. Sydney, Australia (June 2023 - Present). https://www.macquarie.com.au

- Lead data modeling practice across the whole Macquarie enterprise (CGM, RMG, BFS, MacCap, FMG, MAM, LGG, COG)
- Created and secured endorsement of the new enterprise Data Modelling Framework, engaging all group data architects and senior data modelers
- Established and lead Data Modelling Working Group, promoting consistent data modeling standards and processes with more than 120 participants across all groups
- Support group data architects and group data officers in delivering business critical master data models
- Completed POC across various stakeholder groups for the strategic data modeling tool Erwin, securing endorsement by all groups and enterprise Engineering Leadership Team
- Synthesized requirements and designed enterprise target data modeling solution (Erwin, Starburst/Hive bridge, Jira, BitBucket, Collibra, Microsoft Active Directory, source systems)
- Supervised Erwin data modeling solution implementation, providing architectural governance to 8+ internal infrastructure engineering teams and 3+ Erwin vendor teams
- Lead engagement with Erwin Vendor Product team to design and deliver Jira and Erwin API integration for market release
- Design architecture and integration patterns for medallion architecture AWS data platforms: AWS S3, Hive Metastore, Airflow, Starburst Presto, Redshift
- Design architecture and integration patterns for GCP data platforms: Cloud Storage, BigQuery, DBT, Cloud SQL
- Support reimplementation of Collibra data governance platform, producing relevant architecture and integration patterns
- Contribute to enterprise data architecture strategy and data architecture standards

Accomplishments:

- Implemented Erwin target data modeling solution on scope and with in target deadlines (Erwin Data Modeler, Erwin Mart, Erwin ER360, Microsoft Active Directory SSO, Jira, BitBucket, Starburst/Hive, Redshift, JSON, BigQuery, Azure VM for MacOS)
- Delivered enterprise Data Modelling Framework, actively operationalised across all Macquarie groups
- Promoted Data Modeling standard in Enterprise Data Architecture list of standards, that mandates data modelling across all Macquarie groups
- Increased the number of the groups adopting enterprise data modeling tool from 1 to 7, out of all 8 groups (COG, CGM, RMG, BFS, LGG, FMG, MacCap)
- Groups delivered more than 70% of business-critical master data models
- Phased out tactical data modelling tool Enterprise Architect Sparx

Data Services Officer, Charter Hall, vertically integrated investment fund. Sydney, Australia (April 2021 – June 2023). https://www.charterhall.com.au

- Led data and business intelligence function
- Managed end to end group data infrastructure (Azure)
- Led a team of Microsoft BI stack developers
- Devised and maintain current and target data architecture diagrams
- Working closely with solution architects, advised on solution architecture design from data integrity, quality, and accessibility perspective
- Formulated data infrastructure development standards and physical data modelling principles for dimensional enterprise data warehouse and Azure Analysis Service tabular data model, leveraging Kimball methodology
- Designed enterprise data model extensions for strategic business initiative and produce POC's to support Bi developers implementing model changes
- Developed conceptual and logical data models reflecting data domains across internal, 3rd party, and public data
- Devised design and delivered data integrations from variety of sources utilizing SSIS, Azure Logic Apps, API's, Databricks, Data Factory, Power Automate, SFTP file drops, Database replications, Simego, Synapse Analytics, extracting and loading structured and unstructured data into the Azure data lake
- Managed self-service BI program with 10+ citizen PowerBi developers
- Worked closely with senior business stakeholders to scope and drive business outcomes by means of data and BI solutions; liaised with stakeholders from various business and IT departments to secure funding and cross functional resources when required
- Led design and implementation of enterprise Data Access Management solution centralising role-based access management, formalising data classification, introducing data lineage (AAS, Active Directory, Databricks, Purview)
- Led Master Data Management initiative in the capacity of Data Architect alongside Chief Technology and Information Officer (Profisee, Databricks, Data Factory)

Accomplishments:

- Formulated a variety of data quality frameworks, production change controls, standardized templates, data modeling and solution design principles, that are widely adopted in the business and assure consistent quality of BI solutions delivered both by IT and citizen developers
- Shifted business towards utilizing single enterprise data model and consolidated all legacy data models into one
- Increased enterprise grade BI solutions usage across the business by more than 50%
- Designed and supervised implementation of Master Data Management solutions for core business dimensions and definitions

Business Intelligence Developer, Charter Hall (Australia (December 2019 – April 2021).

- Designed BI solutions and underlying physical architecture across all Microsoft BI layers: SSIS source system data loading, dimensional data warehouse design, AAS tabular data modeling, PowerBi Service reporting, in order to create efficiencies in the business and instantly serve business with relevant insights
- Engaged with senior executives and business stakeholders to assess and evaluate their reporting needs and existing business processes to drive performance metrics, free up working hours, and secure business continuity
- Designed and developed business intelligence solutions building blocks that could have been easily reused and transferred from one solution to another promptly serving rapidly growing Charter Hall business and its reporting and automation requirements
- Designed and developed data integrations flowing data between source systems creating process efficiencies and supporting data integrity across the business
- Leveraged BI Infrastructure, Simego integration services and Azure applications to integrate data between business systems and third party solutions to reduce integration costs and create processes efficiencies (Yardi ERP, CRM Dynamics, MRI, OneVue etc)
- Assessed source system current design, scope new feature requirements and engaged with third party partners supervising development and implementation
- Developed ad hoc enhancements for the existing BI solutions
- Provided BI stack training to all IT streams team members to increase the awareness about Charter Hall BI capabilities and enable IT team members to develop their own BI solutions for IT operational purposes
- Together with business stakeholders assessed quality of their data and provided data quality and data integrity recommendations
- Coordinated offshore BI developer to scope and provide requirements relevant to support tickets and enhancements they worked on, reviewed their work on the completion
- Supported Data Governance program implementation across BI infrastructure

PowerBi Developer, Charter Hall (October 2018 – December 2019).

- Rolled out numerous enterprise grade PowerBi service reports for Fund management, Property operations, Investor Relationships, Leasing activities, consumed by business analysts, mid-level and senior management including Charter Hall CEO
- Worked closely with senior stakeholders to gather requirements and created entity relationship diagrams using Erwin
- Contributed to the enterprise data warehouse design using Kimball/Dimensional modeling methodology
- Designed, developed and optimised AAS tabular data models with live connection to the Enterprise Data Warehouse
- Designed and developed PowerBi desktop data models connected to Excel, Sharepoint, and Direct Query data sources
- Wrote ETL SSIS data load packages in SQL and C# loading data into the data warehouse from source system databases and Excel
- Developed Azure SFTP file drops to consume data from external data sources
- Wrote DAX measures with particularly complex syntax supporting periodic financial reporting
- Analysed and optimised performance of existing DAX measures in DAX Studio
- Developed standardised design and development guidelines and report templates for PowerBi solutions
- Hired, coached and coordinated work of two other PowerBi developers (onshore and offshore)
- Ran Data Literacy initiative across the business uplifting business users` BI capabilities

Business Development Analyst, HASSELL, architecture practice. Sydney, Australia (May 2016 – Present). https://www.hassellstudio.com

- Performed PowerBi data modelling aggregating and reconciling data from multiple databases (CRM Dynamics and AXs)
- Designed and administrated standardised PowerBi reports and dashboards providing holistic performance and forecasting information against every business unit and various time periods servicing a pool of more than 100 end users including Executive board members, CEO, Regional and Market Sector senior management
- Defined ETL process and structure underlying PowerBi core data model for secure and efficient data sourcing
- Supervised performance and development of SSAS OLAP cubes as a composite of PowerBi ETL and a standalone reporting tool
- Maintained PowerBi testing and development environments
- Developed source systems validation rules and supervised scheduled data cleansing procedures
- Supervised development of the CRM Dynamics system servicing more than 200 users
- Liaised with project sponsors and stakeholders to scope functional requirements for CRM features and workflows
- Developed and sign off solution demos with project sponsors
- Formulated technical brief and developed detailed solution development critical path/s for the IT team
- Supervised testing and deployment
- Wrote SQL statements to capture data and populate new custom CRM Dynamics fields and database columns
- Wrote XML code for custom CRM Dynamics visualisations
- Provided ad hoc data and business analysis service to various business departments: Business development, Executive board, HR, Finance, Marketing
- Wrote SQL queries to interrogate SQL server databases directly for ad hoc in-depth data analysis

Accomplishments:

- Embedded profitability analysis in bid review automation
- Reduced volume of low fee low profit projects by 5%
- Introduced CRM validation that increased AX and CRM cross system common key success rate from 67% to 100%
- Developed client ranking algorithm to increase volume of high profit projects

Digital Marketing Analyst, The OCA Group, Intueri Education Group. Sydney, Australia (June 2015 – April 2016). http://www.onlinecoursesaustralia.edu.au/

- Administrated cross system data management and supervised IT data integrity projects
- Scoped Salesforce and partner API integrations
- Issued monthly marketing and sales performance reports with tactical and strategic recommendations to CEO, senior management, and Board of investors

- Administrated sales and marketing reports and dashboards across Salesforce, Pardot and Google Analytics
- Designed marketing automations and drip EDM campaign logic in Pardot
- Provided customer base segmentation and cluster analysis in SPSS
- Interrogated SQL student data base to design post acquisition campaigns, up sell and cross sell sales campaigns, increase length of student lifecycle and course completion rates
- Provided analytical insights for ad hoc business initiatives such as product bundling, customer geo-localization, customer satisfaction
- Formulated forecasting logic for sales and marketing teams
- Analyzed marketing channel performance and advised on marketing channels portfolio management

Accomplishments:

- Wrote script and implemented multifactor lead rating algorithm in Salesforce
- Wrote solution logic and supervised implementation of marketing channel tracking consolidation
- Delivered Delacon call tracking implementation
- Delivered Pardot marketing automation implementation
- Introduced monthly performance reports

Various Roles in Analytics, IT Development, and Project Management, Various companies (June 2007 – May 2015)

EDUCATION:

The Open Group

TOGAF Enterprise Architecture Practitioner (TOGAF 10) (September 2024)

AWS

Architecting Solutions on AWS (June 2024)

Databricks

Data Engineering with Databricks (September 2022)

Melbourne Business School

MBA, concentration in Strategy. Melbourne, Australia (September 2011 - December 2011).

Tel Aviv University

MBA. Sofaer MBA Scholarship. Tel Aviv, Israel (September 2010 - August 2011).

Russian State University for the Humanities

Bachelor and Masters of Science in Psychology. Russian State University for the Humanities Scholarship. Moscow, Russia (September 2004 -December 2009).

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND METHODOLOGIES:

<u>Data governance</u>: Collibra, Alation, Informatica, Profisee, Purview, Databricks Unity Catalog

Storage: Microsoft SQL Server, Teradata, Redshift, GCP/BigQuery, Azure DataLake, AWS/Hive/S3

Data integration: Azure Data Factory, Databricks, API's, Azure Logic Apps, Simego, Microsoft Synapse

Analytics, Microsoft Power Automate, SSIS

<u>Data Modeling</u>: Enterprise Architect Sparx, Erwin

<u>Data visualization and reporting</u>: PowerBi, SSRS, Tableau, Visio, 5dChart, Excel, Draw.io

Query and programming languages: SQL, DAX, XML, SPSS syntax

Methodologies: PMBOK (project management body of knowledge), DMBOK (data management body of

knowledge), Agile, Scrum, Kimball, Data Vault, TOGAF Enterprise Architecture

ERP: Yardi, MRI, AX

CRM: Salesforce, 365 CRM Dynamics, Shopify, custom CRM's

Marketing automations and EDM systems: Mailchimp, Pardot

Online marketing analysis: Google Analytics (attribution modelling), Optimizely (A/B and multivariate testing),

Pardot (lead nurturing and closed loop marketing analytics), Qlikview

Online advertising platforms: Adwords, Critero, Adroll, Facebook, Bing Ads

Content management and analysis: Umbraco, Magento, PhraseApp, Inspectlet (heatmaps), custom CMS's

REFERENCES: On request.